{
        "DIETS" : [ 
            {
                "question": "The mode of obtaining food for growth, energy, repair, and maintenance is called?",
                "option1": "Carbohydrate",
                "option2": "Nutrition",
                "option3": "Calorie",
                "option4": "Fatty Acid",
                "answer": "Calorie"
            }, 
            {
                "question": "All of the following are the components of foods except_____.",
                "option1": "Carbohydrates",
                "option2": "Proteins",
                "option3": "Vitamins",
                "option4": "Fiber",
                "answer": "Fiber"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following are called macronutrients?",
                "option1": "Carbohydrates, Proteins, and Vitamins",
                "option2": "Minerals, Proteins, and Vitamins",
                "option3": "Carbohydrates, Proteins, and Fats",
                "option4": "Proteins, Fats, and Minerals.",
                "answer": "Carbohydrates, Proteins, and Fats"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which components of food are called body builder?",
                "option1": "Carbohydrates",
                "option2": "Protiens",
                "option3": "Vitamins",
                "option4": "Minerals",
                "answer": "Proteins"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following are the primary products of photosynthesis?",
                "option1": "Proteins",
                "option2": "Carbohydrates",
                "option3": "Minerals",
                "option4": "Water",
                "answer": "Carbohydrates"
            },
            {
                "question": "Condensation of glucose molecules (C6H12O6) results in",
                "option1": "Starch",
                "option2": "Celulose",
                "option3": "Glycogen",
                "option4": "Glucagon",
                "answer": "Glucagon"
            },
            {
                "question": "The brain and RBC needs energy source in the form of",
                "option1": "Proteins",
                "option2": "Glucose",
                "option3": "Fats",
                "option4": "Enzymes",
                "answer": "Glucose"
            },
            {
                "question": "The human body uses carbohydrates in the form of____.",
                "option1": "Glucose",
                "option2": "Glycogen",
                "option3": "Starch",
                "option4": "Enzymes",
                "answer": "Glucose"
            },
            {
                "question": "In which form body stores glucose?",
                "option1": "Cellulose",
                "option2": "Starch",
                "option3": "Glycogen and cellulose",
                "option4": "Glycogen",
                "answer": "Glycogen"
            }
        ],
        "CoVID": [
            {
                "question": "The first case of novel coronavirus was identified in .....",
                "option1": "Beijing",
                "option2": "Shanghai",
                "option3": "Wuhan, Hubei",
                "option4": "Tiajin",
                "answer": "Wuhan, Hubei"
            },
            {
                "question":"Mild Symptoms of Novel coronavirus are:",
                "option1":"Fever",
                "option2":"Cough",
                "option3":"Shortness of Breadth",
                "option4":"All the above",
                "answer":"All the above"
            },
            {
                "question":"Which of the following diseases are related to coronavirus?",
                "option1":"MERS",
                "option2":"SARS",
                "option3":"Both 1 and 2",
                "option4":"Neither 1 nor 2",
                "answer":"Both 1 and 2"
            },
            {
                "question":"Name a clinical trial in which blood is transfused from recovered COVID-19 patients to a coronavirus patient who is in critical condition?",
                "option1":"Plasma Therapy",
                "option2":"Solidarity",
                "option3":"Remdesivir",
                "option4":"Hydroxychloroquine",
                "answer":"Plasma Therapy"
            },
            {
                "question":"In a study, which cells are found in COVID-19 patients 'bode well' for long-term immunity?",
                "option1":"P-cell",
                "option2":"D-cell",
                "option3":"T-cell",
                "option4":"Endothelial Cells",
                "answer":"T-cells"
            },
            {
                "question":"In India, when did the second phase of COVID-19 vaccination start?",
                "option1":"December 2020",
                "option2":"January 2021",
                "option3":"February 2021",
                "option4":"March 2021",
                "answer": "March 2021"
            },
            {
                "question":"How many countries, areas, or territories are suffering from novel coronavirus outbreaks in the World?",
                "option1":"More than 50",
                "option2":"More than 100",
                "option3":"More than 150",
                "option4":"More than 200",
                "answer": "More than 200"
            },
            {
                "question":"Thailand announced that it has proceeded to test it's novel coronavirus vaccine on which animal/bird?",
                "option1":"Monkeys",
                "option2":"Lizards",
                "option3":"Hens",
                "option4":"Kites",
                "answer": "Monkeys"
            },
            {
                "question":"Name the vaccine that is jointly developed by the German company BioNTech and US pharma giant Pfizer for COVID-19?",
                "option1":"BNT162",
                "option2":"PICOVACC",
                "option3":"Both A and B",
                "option4":"Neither A nor B",
                "answer": "BNT162"
            },
            {
                "question":"From where coronavirus got its name?",
                "option1":"crown-like projections",
                "option2":"leaf-like projections",
                "option3":"surface structure of bricks",
                "option4":"None of the above",
                "answer": "crown-like projections"
            }
        ],
        "CURR_AFF": [
            {
                "question": "‘Alpine Plant species’, which are critically endangered have been discovered in which state?",
                "option1": "Assam",
                "option2": "Sikkim",
                "option3": "Arunachal Pradesh",
                "option4": "Himachal Pradesh",
                "answer": "Arunachal Pradesh"
            },
            {
                "question":"Which state approved a law to give life imprisonment to food adulterators?",
                "option1":"Kerala",
                "option2":"Tamil Nadu",
                "option3":"Karnataka",
                "option4":"Madhya Pradesh",
                "answer":"Madhya Pradesh"
            },
            {
                "question":"When is the ‘Zero Discrimination Day’ observed annually across the world?",
                "option1":"March 1",
                "option2":"March 2",
                "option3":"March 3",
                "option4":"March 4",
                "answer":"March 1"
            },
            {
                "question":"What is the name of the third Scorpene-class submarine that has been inducted into the Indian Navy recently?",
                "option1":"INS Kanakalata",
                "option2":"INS Karanj",
                "option3":"INS Chennai",
                "option4":"INS Kolkata",
                "answer":"INS Karanj"
            },
            {
                "question":"Where is India’s first dedicated Express Cargo Terminal launched?",
                "option1":"Mumbai",
                "option2":"Delhi",
                "option3":"Bengaluru",
                "option4":"Chennai",
                "answer":"Bengaluru"
            },
            {
                "question":"Which platform has launched a short-video making feature named ‘Spotlight’?",
                "option1":"Telegram",
                "option2":"WhatsApp",
                "option3":"Snapchat",
                "option4":"Tik Tok",
                "answer": "Snapchat"
            },
            {
                "question":"Which social media platform has launched a campaign called ‘It’s Between You’, in India?",
                "option1":"WhatsApp",
                "option2":"Twitter",
                "option3":"TikTok",
                "option4":"Telegram",
                "answer": "WhatsApp"
            },
            {
                "question":"Samsung India partnered with which major technology company to train offline retailers about digital technologies?",
                "option1":"Amazon",
                "option2":"Facebook",
                "option3":"Google",
                "option4":"Apple",
                "answer": "Facebook"
            },
            {
                "question":"Google is set to launch its second cloud region in which Indian city?",
                "option1":"Gurugram",
                "option2":"Hyderabad",
                "option3":"Bengaluru",
                "option4":"Delhi",
                "answer": "Delhi"
            },
            {
                "question":"From where coronavirus got its name?",
                "option1":"crown-like projections",
                "option2":"leaf-like projections",
                "option3":"surface structure of bricks",
                "option4":"None of the above",
                "answer": "crown-like projections"
            }
        ],
        "SPORTS": [
            {
                "question": "Grand Slam is used in which of the following games?",
                "option1": "Lawn Tennis",
                "option2": "Football",
                "option3": "Badminton",
                "option4": "Cricket",
                "answer": "Lawn Tennis"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who holds the record for the most runs in all the Cricket World Cup tournaments?",
                "option1": "Viv Richards",
                "option2": "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "option3": "Shane Warne",
                "option4": "Brian Lara",
                "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"
                
            },
            {
                "question": "How many medals have been won by the India Men’s Hockey team at Asian Games till date?",
                "option1": "11",
                "option2": "9",
                "option3": "15",
                "option4": "3",
                "answer": "15"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which player is given the Golden Glove Award?",
                "option1": "Best player",
                "option2": "Best Goal-keeper",
                "option3": "Top Goal-scorer",
                "option4": "Player aged 21 or younger", 
                "answer": "Best Goal-keeper"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which sport’s competition is known as the “Big Bash League”?",
                "option1": "Football",
                "option2": "Volleyball",
                "option3": "BasketBall",
                "option4": "Cricket", 
                "answer": "Cricket"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who is the winner of the US Open 2019 Men's title?",
                "option1": "Roger Federer",
                "option2": "Rafael Nadal",
                "option3": "Daniil Medvedev",
                "option4": "Novak Djokovic",
                "answer": "Rafael Nadal"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the new name of Feroz Shah Kotla ground?",
                "option1": "Arun Jaitley Stadium",
                "option2": "Sheila Dikshit Stadium",
                "option3": "Gautam Gambhir Stadium",
                "option4": "Ajit Wadekar Stadium",
                "answer": "Arun Jaitley Stadium"
                
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following region has won the Ranji Trophy tournament 2019?",
                "option1": "Saurashtra",
                "option2": "Mumbai",
                "option3": "Vidarbha",
                "option4": "Rajasthan",
                "answer": "Vidarbha"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who got FIFA Best Player 2019 Award?",
                "option1": "Neymar",
                "option2": "L. Messi",
                "option3": "C. Ronaldo",
                "option4": "Luka Mordic", 
                "answer": "L. Messi"
            },
            {
                "question": "Pankaj Advani recently won his 22nd World Billiards Title 2019. This tournament is held in..",
                "option1": "Malaysia",
                "option2": "Myanmar",
                "option3": "India",
                "option4": "Russia", 
                "answer": "Myanmar"
            }
        ]
    
}